Guide to the Rioghan Kirchner Civil Rights in Brooklyn Collection BCMS.0011
Brooklyn Collection
- Series IV: Black News
  - Volume 1
    - No. 19, 1970 August 15 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      More Letters to the editor
      A brother... On voter registration
    - No. 20, 1970 September (Box 6, Folder 3)
      International day of solidarity…People of Mozambique
      The white women's liberation
      Saga of Queen Mother Moore and Mother Langley
      Here comes de judge you bloodsuckers
      Sickle cell anemia
      College students
      Give the service where it's needed, Bd. of Health
      An open letter to all brothers
      Three homes
      "Our seed, our fruit" (a poem)
    - No. 21, 1970 September 26 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      Zionist bubbles from the deep
      "Question Sis. A,c" (a poem)
      American justice or injustice
      An appeal to 1,000 brothers saved from the draft
      Politics in Jamaica
      Doctor I'm Dying
      "Mama's tears" (a poem)
      History lesson from a reader
      Crumbs from ole massa's table
      Get in the habit of helping each other
      Xmas
      Black theatre
    - No. 22, 1970 October 14 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      Women's liberation
      Save the homes. Save the families
      The evolution of arrogance
      For real or not for real
      The battle of Amman
      "The Black woman returns" (a poem)
      We want you Black Man
      All Black inmates are political prisoners
      "Ancient mother rhythm" (a poem)
      Damn Nigger fool
      These three jury incidents are true
      Uhuru Sasa school schedule
      Pig brutality on the Black community
      Save the homes, save the families
      UFT Zionism at 271
      A new look at political dogma
      So young and yet so old
      Storm in a negro teapot
    - No. 23, 1970 November 3 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      Cairo
      The spirit of youth, wisdom of age
      "Brothers" (a poem)
      The brilliance of Black folks
      Umoja
      Nat Cooper (Ad)
      "Can I hear America singing?" (a poem)
      "Elevation of a thought" (a poem)
      "U'm me" (a poem)
      From Roxbury to Rio and back in a hurry
      American Documentary films Inc.
      Just Who are the savages?
      Black writers – Jazz museums
    - No. 24, 1970 November 20 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      Angela
      Three families
      The conference goer
      Getting rid of some bed-bugs
      Blockheaded fools
      Tombs: Ninth floor
      "Tombs" (a poem)
      "Expressions of appreciation to the Black woman" (a poem)
      What defense fund for Angela?
      Black political takeover
      Black solidarity day and Minister Farrakhan
      Minister Farrakhan
      Prodigal anti-poverty son
      Anatomy of a revolution
      Black removal in Fort Green
      Conditions pertaining to Black people in Australia
      Opening night at the New Heritage Theater
    - No. 25, 1970 December 10 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      The new breed of Black youth
      Another pinch for the poor
      Channel 11 editorial
      Black education
      Eastern Regional conference
      Angela and Aretha – spirit and soul
      Toombs...9th floor
      Death by any means necessary
      Mr. Angle Hair Jones
      The pusher
      The real issue: consciousness
      Third World Conference
      Ododo at the Negro Ensemble Company
    - No. 26, 1970 December 27 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      The Myth Of Methadone
      Mercenaries of Mays
      Tombs
      Spirits of Our Forebears
      Oreo Radicals
      The Devil Catchers are at The New Lafayette Theatre
      The Jonathon P. Jackson Commune
      Invasion of Guinea By Portugal
      For The Peoples Health
      Nyere
      Around Our Way – Big Black
      Cairo, Illinois
    - No. 27, 1971 January 14 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      The New Breed of Black Youth (Story of the African-American Student Association)
      The News Media: Racism On The Front Line
      Natural Food For Survival
      Three Months Reprieve – (3Families)
      Guyana's Bauxite
      Around The Far East
      East Coast Educational Conference
      For Immediate Release (Cairo Illinois)
      Eugenics, Birth Control And The Black Man
      Model Cities
    - No. 28, 1971 February 7 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      Murder By Any Other Name Is Murder (Prison Conditions)
      The News Media Front Line Defense
      The Brother Is Trying To Survive
      Natural Food Column
      Repression on The Rise
      Minister Louis Farrakhan's Speech at Rally For Angela Davis
      Brownsville and its Terrible Drug Problem
      New Black Political Party
      Death of a Black Woman...Sequel to Minister Farrakhan's Speech
      Will We Be Prepared?
      Who Is To Blame?? The N.Y.C. Transit Authority
    - No. 29, 1971 February 25 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      Malcolm In Perspective
      Satire From Lil Man
      Current Status of The Three Families
      Howard Houses
      Don't Talk Too Much Black Juror
      An Open Letter
      Angela Davis A Question Of Strategy
      The Tombs (Rebellion)
      Support The Haitian Resistance
    - No. 30, 1971 March 28 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      Minister Farrakhan at The East
      Lower East Side School Board Struggle
      Amiri Baraka (Leroy Jones at The East)
      Fasting As A Revolutionary Concept
      Ground Breaking Banditry
      Ahmed Evans
      There's A Beautiful City; Or The Seizure of Dr. Strangelove's Wealth
      Niggers In The Revolutionary Woodpile
      Amiri Baraka At Kimako's
      Fuss in Uganda
      Three Families
      A Report On The Memorial Of Malcolm X
      Malcolm X's Weekend
      B.S.P.P. Pre Convention
    - No. 31, 1971 May 7 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Get The Pusher
      Uganda, Guinea Events Lessons And Tasks For Africa
      Kutoa Unoja – A Poem
      Black Culture In Perspective
      Spring Happenings At The East
      Another Community Crisis
      Structuring Black Theatre
      Mantan Moreland And The House Niggers Of Revolution
      Second Black Political Convention
    - No. 32, 1971 May 29 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Malcolm X on Religion
      Manifesto For A Black Revolutionary Party
      Get You A Gun
      Subways
      Words From Our Brother In Captivity Poetry
      Experience In Black Theatre
      Swanee- The Terrible
      When The Mugger Starts Closing In
      The Gay Babylonian Marxist
      Reparations- The Ministry of Justice Republic of New Africa
      World Solidarity Day - May 25,1971
    - No. 33, 1971 July 17 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Niggers At Essence
      Firefighters Exam
      A Yoruban Wedding at The East
      White Suburban Teachers Union Vs. Black New Ark
      The Beast Wants The Black Community To Burn
      On The Struggle Against Dope
      Last Chance To Save The Maurice Fredricks
      The Destruction of Central Brooklyn
    - No. 34, 1971 September 10 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Budweiser Racism
      Terror On 39th St. Flatbush
      Strategy and Tactics of A Pan African
      Nationalist Party
      Bro Baraka
      Editorial: The Negro Integrationists are At It Again
      Isn't It Nation Time?
      Around Our Way – By Big Black
      Black Actors in The Public Theatre
      Uncle Sam's Budget
      Isaac Hayes Sings Foe his Listeners and Not For DJ's
      Isaac Hayes At The Apollo
      Freedom By Any Means Necessary – A poem
      Model Cities' Method of Repressing The Black Nation
      Negro Leftist Flunkies
      Stop The Boy's Rip-off (3 Families)
      Reflections On The Murder of Bro. George Jackson
      A Closer Look At Ida
      News Release: United Front Of Cairo
      Africa's Reactionary B's Trounced
      Cabs
    - No. 35, 1971 October 22 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Attica
      Nation Time Means Our Own Police
      A Magnolia In Brooklyn
      A Song In Blood and Tears
      Eight Pitfalls of Nationalism
      Stop The Boy's Ripoff (3 Homes)
      Conversation With Lee Morgan
      Racism In Criminal Courts
      Two Views on Sweetback
      The Law Of Movement
      Around Our Way By Big Black
    - No. 36, 1971 December (Box 7, Folder 2)
      Our African Correspondent
      The Joy Of Learning
      Letters To The Editor (See Wilmington KKK)
      Your Thoughts
      Just Ask for "Something Beautiful By Lumumba"
      Black History and White Control
      Ma Bell
      The Three Homes Are Saved
      Black Theatre Review
      Night Of The Ball
      St. Mary's Hospital
      Black Contempt For Blaci
    - No. 37, 1972 January (Box 7, Folder 2)
      A South African Revolutionary
      Anderson Ave. Tenant's League
      Black News View on Attica
      File Briefs Challenging City Attempt To Evict 2 Bed-Stuy Families
      Around Our Way – by Big Black
      Accused By A Black Informer
      America and Childbirth
      Why Blacks Collaborate with White Racists
      James Barksdale – Justice for the Poor And Black
      A Struggle In Florida
      We Must Support Our Own
      Kamuzu Banda's Kowtow To South Africa
      Black Solidarity Day
      Africa Reports
      Tom Ridin Shotgun
      Concerning The Rent Strike
      Pulse Of The Community
    - No. 38, 1972 February (Box 7, Folder 2)
      The Greater Lower East Side Struggle
      Reflections On The Bus Strike
      Black News' Position On The Stars
      Hooliganism: Another Enemy
      Crucifixion of the Harlem 6
      Statements by Tony Brown Executive Producer, Black Journal Dec. 29, 1971
      Newark, New Jersey Black Liberation Flag Issue
      Oriental Jews or Jewish Arabs?
      Operational Black Unity
      Divided We Fall
      Join The Family
      No Limitation To Imitation
      Uhuru Sasa Shule
      Information On Methadone
      Message To The Hustlers
      The Hidden Attackers
      A Letter To A SisterPress Release- Congress of African People
    - No. 39, 1972 April (Box 7, Folder 2)
      Black News' Position On African Nationalism
      Brother Al Vann
      A Mobile Clinic For Our Community
      Concerned Citizens of Brownsville
      Around Our Way- by Big Black
      Chattel Slavery
      White Merchants and Black Power
      Heroin Maintenance
      Lift Every Voice And Sing
      Thoughts
      Background information on Zimbabwe
    - No. 40, 1972 May (Box 7, Folder 2)
      Young Gifted And Black, But Their Souls Not Hardly Intact
      Beware The Cable
      Open Letter To Our Colored Station WBLS; The Plantation, Formerly Known As WLIB
      African Liberation Day Coordinating Committee
      An Open Letter to Black Nationalists
      Maulana Ron Karenga
      Editorial - Wrong Political Direction
      It's Hard Work Time
      Kujichagulia – Self Determination
      Silently the Beast Stalks the Sleeping Giant
      The Trials And Tribulations of Judge Wright
      Answering a Lame Rationalization
      On The Mobile Health Van
      The Sharpville Massacre
      Anatomy of Roy Innis
    - No. 41, 1972 July (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Final Tribute To Kwame Nkrumah
      Why Must They Die?
      A Black Judge Looks At "Justice" In South Africa
      The Power Hungry Black Nationalist
      Black Repression In Wilmington N.C.
      Joint Apprenticeship Program
      What The "Brownie Point System Is All About
      An Experience In Fort Green Center
      Buck and The Preacher
      Taking The Cost Of Repairs Out Of The Rent
      Whose Puddle Do I Be Standing In?
      A mans' Home is City's Castle
      By Only A Handful
      On Subscriptions
    - No. 42, 1972 August (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Some Thoughts On Nation Building
      Report" International Commission Of Jurists
      Even Liberals Love To Blackface
      Around Our Way-by Jetu Weusi (Formerly Big Black) CORE Responds To Integrationist attack On It's Leaders
      Ghanians: Save Kwame Knrumah From The Enemies
      Racism In The Building Trades
      The Three Families
      Word From The Motherland
      Plank To End Mortgage Assessment Tax
      Girls Grow Up To Become Women
      Attention: Murder Of Earl Kenneth Walker - Student
      The Man (the Boy)
    - No. 43, 1972 October (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Death To The Pusher
      Interview With Mrs. Louise Boyd
      On Two Different Black Businesses
      Press Conference: by Hon. Wanume Kiebedi, Minister of Foreign Affairs of The Republic of Uganda
      Angela Davis
      Son Of Darkness (Poem)
      An Open Letter By Jetu Weusi (Formerly Big Black)
      Don't Be Naïve and Gullible
      Attica – Revisited: Monday Bloody Monday
      Israeli, South African Diamonds Under Focus
      Towards An African Nationalist Party
      My Son A Warrior (poem)
      Pan African Skills project Recruits Blacks
      Ending The Three Families Appeal
      Summation On The Three Families
      Another House Threatened
      Children Are The Future: Uhura Sasa School
      African Liberation Day- speech by Kumbirai Kannga, North American Representative of Zanu
      Sickle Cell
      Goin' to The People
      What Is Nationhood - Talk or Substance?
      Black Unity Conference
      Keep Muse Alive
      Newsletter - San Quentin
      Prison Column
      WWRI...Enemy Of The Black Community
      Lets Support Our Motherland
      On The Significance Kwame Nkrumah and Nkrumahism
      St. Louis Two: "Blood" Railroaded
      Come On Home Sister
      The Eloquence of Debate...Another Ancient African Art
    - No. 44, 1972 November (Box 7, Folder 4)
      The Nigger Mugger
      Captivator (a Poem)
      Sounder
      Black News Circulation
      Al Vann
      The S.S. Goodship Rockaway
      Relativity
      Around Our Way – by Kasisi Jitu Weusi
      An Afternoon With Helen Morgan
      One Bloody Nite
      All-African Women's Conference, Dar es-Salaam, Tanzania
      Blackest September (a Poem)
      Brownsville Parents Struggle Against The Board of Education
      Treatment and Racist Parents
    - No. 45, 1973 January (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Wanted: A choice of Treatment
      The Pulverizing Might Of The Black Masses
      On Bad Tendencies On The Black Movement - A Criticism
      Black News: Mouthpiece of The Black Masses
      A New Government Is Born
      A Racist Letter To The Editor
      Why You Burning Down All The Churches Whitey?
      How To Teach Black Children
    - No. 46, 1973 March 15 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Chairman Attends Funeral
      Sisters Rap
      Editor Replaced
      African Children's World
      For Ebony Ladies Only
      Message From The American Liberation Army
      The Think Machine: Black Is... (poem)
      Letters To The Editor - Long Live The Spirit Of Bro. Mark Essex
      The Establishment Press
      Message To Our Black "Brothers" In Con Edison From Blhem
      How To Teach Black Children, PART 2
      Around Our Way - by Jitu Weusi
      Notes On Our Readers From Africa
      The Voice Of Young Africa
      Death At An Early Age
      In The Final Analysis
  - Volume 2
    - No. 1, 1973 April 1 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      Mark Essex: Fanatic?
      Why Malcolm X was assassinated
      Inside Tanzania
      Poverty Pimps
      A Black Survival Curriculum
      Round Our Way – Jitu Weusi
      Mke Weusi (Black woman)
      Weusi Kubba (Black art)
      Alive at the East
      Community Tax Service
      Martin Sostra: American justice
      The Right to have children
      P.O.W.'s forum
      "Truth is on the way" poem
      Independent Black education
      Today's plantation (U.S. Post Office)
      Uhuru Sasa evening school
      Nommo - 3 levels of Black folk
      International Day of Solidarity For African Prisoners of War
      Sema Tena – (Say it Again)
      USS Kitty Hawk "Riot"
      Editorial - Belated Tribute To a Brother Man
    - No. 2, 1973 April 15 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      Mtumwa Kwa Sabubu Ya Siasa- (political prisoner)
      Building Blackness
      To Our Brothers??? "On The Force"
      Terrorism
      Who Is Charles Cannon??
      Around Our Way by Kasisi Jitu Weusi
      Mke Weusi (Black Woman)
      Weusi Kumba
      Black Music
      P.O.W.'s Forum
      Checking It Out
      Black Australia
      Food For Thought
      Community News
      Independent Black Education
      Sema Tena (Say it Again)
      Black Bermuda
      Editorial
    - No. 3, 1973 May 1 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      JHS 57 The New School
      I Am Albert Washington
      Around Our Way - By Kasisi Jitu Weusi
      Mwanake Weusi (Black Woman)
      Weusi Kuumba – Black Art
      Nation Building
      Well Done Brothers
      Mwanamke Weusi (Black Woman)
      Council Independent Black Institutions Presents
      Black Parents Convention
      No More Black Babies
      For Rap (last day of the Trial March 27)
      Rockefeller
      Editorial - The Monster In Our Midst
    - No. 4, 1973 June 2 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      AFRIKA IS AT WAR
      Boycott Gulf
      The Credit Ripoff
      Self Defense (part One)
      Sister Joanne; A Black Woman
      Africa Foe Africans: When?
      Letters To The Editor (birth control)
      The Case of The Charlotte 3
      Around Our Way - by Kasisi Jitu Weusi
      Weusi Kuumba (Black Creativity)
      From Washington: Dark City
      A View On Black Survival
      Sema Tena, Say it Again
    - No. 5, 1973 June 30 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      Bermuda: A Smoldering Volcano
      Is Amin a Nationalist?
      Guyana. Sanctuary or Slave Trader?
      Caribbean Common Market
      Mwanamke Weusi a poem
      On International Solidarity Day
      From our Puerto Rican Correspondent
      Checking It Out – River Niger
      Why We Use "K"
      Food For Thought: The case against Meat
      To Our People - To Black People
      Self Defense
      Kalande
      Sema-Tena: Say It Again
    - No. 6, 1973 July (Box 8, Folder 2)
      Criteria of Culture
      Maulana Karenga: Reflections on the Meaning of Us
      American Legal Power Over Blacks Challenged
      The Communist Party and The Black Community
      Fundisha: Is It Best For Black People?
      African Liberation Day
      Tanzanian Recruitment
      Boycott GULF
      Black Women Stand Proud
      Another "Wounded Knee Treaty"
      Checking It Out – The "White" Lie In Black History
      Sema-Tena – "Say It Again"
    - No. 7, 1973 August 4 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      The Education Of Sonny Carson
      So That Six Million Africans May Live
      Puerto Rican Community of Park Slope
      Funisha: Congress of African People
      ALD in Antigua
      Poem To The Ghetto Sister
      Mwanamke Weusi: Black Woman
      Street Festival
      Black Winds Of The East
      Editorial (Attacks On Black Leadership)
    - No. 8, 1973 September (Box 8, Folder 2)
      Medical (mis)Treatment!
      He was Sly, But he wasn't No Fox
      Why Is Separation Necessary?
      Fundisha: Congress Of African People
      African Youth Day...
      History of the Pittsburgh Congress of African People
      Around Our Way - by Kais Jitu Weusi
      MTU MPYA
      Sonny Carson
      A Professional Revolutionary Zed Malik Shaker
      From Washington, Dark City
      Food For Thought (Herb Chart For Female Disorders)
      Salad-poem
    - No. 9, 1973 October 1 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      Poem "Little Black Boy"
      Organize Now
      Congratulations (elections)
      Ideological Definitions
      Fundisha, Congress of African People
      Pittsburgh Cap Opens Retail Outlet
      Black Studies, Trouble At Yale
      Around Our Way - by Kasis Jitu Weusi
      Gordon's War Is Our War
      Finally Made It Home
    - No. 10, 1973 October 22 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      Giving Birth Naturally
      Guyana '73
      Black News exclusive Interview with Prime Minister Forbes Burnham
      Fundisha- Congress of African People
      The Israeli War
      Definitions Of Value - Class Struggle
      The Guyana Experience
      Checking It Out. "Que Hacer"
      Eusi Kwayana Speaks
      The Creator My Father (poem)
    - No. 11, 1973 December 11 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      All Men Must Die – Poem
      One Race! One Nation! One Destiny!
      South Afrika In Amerika
      In Memoriam - Twymon Myers
      Fundisha – Congress of African People
      Neo Colonialism No! Pan–Africanism Will save The Motherland
      Black Art
      Around Our Way by Kasis Jitu Weusi
      The Power Of Our Presence
      On The Correct Black Educator
      Checking It Out (The spook Who Sat Too Long)
      Idi Amin on The Middle East
      Kwanza – Our Black Holy Days
      Editorial - It's A Struggle to Struggle
    - No. 12, 1973 December 26 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      Kwanza, Our Black Holy Days
      How To Celebrate Kwanza
      Black Boycott of Senseless Xmas Shopping
      Black Buyers Abused by Mas-X (Xmas)
      The Spiritual Significance of Kwanza
      In the Spirit of Amilicar Cabral
      Fundisha - Congress of African People
      PADC in the Move
      Elitism
      Enemy Of The People
      Food For Thought (by Frederick Douglass)
      Notes On A Little Green Book (Break de Chains)
      "People Put Justice In The Courts"
    - No. 13, 1974 January 28 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      Message To The Black Liberation Army
      Restoration On Restoration
      Uhuru Sasa
      Aid To The Afrikan War Of Liberation
      To Change Our "Slave" Schools
      Two Legendary Leaders of The Afrikan War For Our Liberation
      National Black Parents Code
      Blacks In Sweden
    - No. 14, 1974 February (Box 8, Folder 4)
      Poem For Malcolm X
      An Open Letter to Afrikan P.O.W.'s
      Gary "72" Revisited
      Monday Night – Tuesday Mornin – A Time To Forget
      God Bless The Child That's Got His Own
      Fundisha – Congress Of African People
      To Build The Nationalist-Pan Afrikanist Organization
      We must Understand why Many Black organizations Failed in The Past
      Needed - Revolution in The Caribbean
      How Do You Like Being A Guinea Pig In a Cancer Experiment?
      Walimu Weusi (The Black Teacher)
      Black Youngsters Look At Watergate Nixon
      The Return Of Muhammad Ali
      Where Do Afrikan People Go From Here?
      Black Liberation Flag Week Proclaimed
      Black Students
      A Memorable Day At The East
      Sema Tena
    - No. 15, 1974 March (Box 8, Folder 5)
      Sekou Toure On The Artist...
      Who and What is The Black Artist
      Molombo Means Spirit
      Black Dance
      Slave Ship
      Checking It Out: The Book Of Life
      Fundisha - Congress Of African Peopled
      Albany Under King Rocky
      Tanzanian Notes
      Identity Crisis In The Caribbean
      The Emergence of Pan-African Communications
      On The West Coast Of The United States
      His Spirit Lives On (Kakuyon Olugbala a/k/a Twyman Myers)
      We Would Help You But You're Black
    - No. 16, 1974 April (Box 8, Folder 5)
      African Liberation Day (poem)
      Who Is Afrikan Liberation For?
      The New York Afrikan Liberation Support Committee
      Oppressed People In The Caribbean Are Struggling For Real Change
      A Devil Or A Witch?
      Fundisha Congress Of African People
      Little Rock 74 and Beyond
      Afrikan Women Unite
      Liberation Movement Photographs
      Walimu Weusi - The Black Teacher
      Public Statement By Progressive Eritreans and Ethiopians In Greater
    - No. 17, 1974 May (Box 8, Folder 5)
      From Our Point Of View
      Black News Interviews: Newark Politicians
      Behind the Stella Wright Strike - Part 1
      Coops a New Resource in Housing
      The Black Teacher
      Liberation Begins At Home
      Who Will Protect The Black Community? (police brutality)
      Inside Guinea-Bissau
      6th PAC (Pan African Congress)
      A Prison Dream To You (poem)
    - No. 18, 1974 June (Box 8, Folder 6)
      Black Woman (poem)
      Afrikan Liberation Day
      Get Ready You Mother
      Will We Remain Niggers or Will We Emerge As Black Men?
      Indictment No. 134-68 – Herman Ferguson Case Revisited
      Haitian Refugees or Traitors?
      The Meaning of ALD
      A.L.S.C. Resignation!
      Extend a Brotherly Sisterly Hand
      13 De Mau Mau
      Plainfield, N.J.